James Martin (UK)

DevOps / Infrastructure Engineer

+44 7713 340 536

iames.martin.business@outlook.com

Available immediately for contract or permanent placement in the United Kingdom & Europe

Statement

My skills have been gained through the design, installation and maintenance of IT infrastructures - most recently using public and private cloud offerings but also via appliances hosted internally or at colocation sites. I am also well practiced at migrations between these scenarios.

Most recently I have been using services like Azure, AWS and Digital Ocean to provide flexible and scalable infrastructures, but also have much traditional experience managing wide area networks and using bare metal hypervisors and storage networks to create virtualized infrastructures along with the necessary negotiating with 3rd parties to maintain these critical services.

Having designed and implemented several installations within scope, I am able to communicate effectively and have experience managing small and effective teams.

Among my lifetime interests is software development (Java & C#) which recently has supplemented my infrastructure experience and become very beneficial in some of my more recent short-term development operations related contracts.

Skills

Azure, AWS, Digital Ocean SANs, SMB & NFS Active Directory Equallogic SANs C#, Java, Python Load Balancing Cloud Storage, Containers nginx / Apache Jenkins / Ansible WANs, LANs & TCP/IP
Citrix & Remote Desktop Services
Exchange 2010 / 2013 / 2016
Web filters and Proxies
Javascript, VBscript
High Availability
Virtual Firewalls
HTML, CSS, PHP
Unity3D

VMWare vCenter & ESX
Linux Bash Shell & Powershell
Palo Alto & Cisco Firewalls
Disaster Recovery Planning
OpenVPN, CertBot
GitHub, version control
MySQL, SQL Server
Wordpress, Ghost, CMS
PBX / VOIP / SIP trunks

Qualifications

BSc (Honours) Computing, IT and Business Octo

October 2013

Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA)

February 2010

Via: MCP 070-290, MCP 070-291, MCP 070-293, MCP 070-270

(Also: MCTS: 070-621, MCP 070-271, MCP 070-272)

BTEC: HND Computing September 2000

GCSE's September 1998

Experience

Contract position for a gaming start-up creating a 'League of Legends' style MOBA.

Unity3D with C# was used to create the client/server apps, the servers were hosted on a AWS & DigitalOcean. At the start of the contract my role was mainly infrastructure, as my development skills became apparent I resolved many application-based utilisation issues and assisted with general development in conjunction with the infrastructure duties.

- Used Azure & DigitalOcean to provide front and backend services
- · Linux bash, python and Ansible Towers for admin and automation
- Unity3D, C# with Visual Studio
- Application containers (Kubernetes)
- Knowledge of software version control systems (GitHub, Plastic SCM) and release management
- Configured load balancers, cloud storage, virtual firewalls
- · Completed penetration testing and security policy review

DevOps Consultant

Sep 2016 - Feb 2017

A short term contract working for a Data Analytics and machine learning SME startup who were facing issues with scaling, automation and storage.

- Used AWS & DigitalOcean to provide front and backend services
- MySQL server administration
- Linux bash, python and Ansible Towers for admin and automation
- Application containers (Kubernetes)
- · Configured load balancers, cloud storage, virtual firewalls

IT Infrastructure Manager

Lorica Insurance Brokers

Jan 2011 - Jul 2016 5 Years 7 Months

Lorica Insurance Brokers expanded to 8 branches around the country and I was promoted to an infrastructure management role within the senior management team; a rewarding and challenging position in which I work with some very talented, inspiring and driven individuals.

- Ensuring the infrastructure can react flexibly to increases in headcount
- · Administration of software licensing
- Design and Implementation of a Palo Alto VPN solution for our serviced offices
- Major contributions towards IT strategy and annual budgeting
- Authoring business processes and procedure documentation
- · Assist with the transition towards a service driven environment
- Hardware lifecycle management
- IT security profile design and responsibility

Senior Business Systems Support

Lorica Insurance Brokers

Feb 2009 - Jan 2011 2 Years

An ambitious and innovative company providing general commercial insurance solutions with (at the time) 5 branches around the country. During this period of my career I lead the transition from combined IT services hosted by a sister organisation 'Lorica Consulting' - this included the design and implementation of:

- An MPLS network spanning 5 sites
- Redundant VMWare vCenter environment hosted on Dell Equallogic SAN hardware
- Citrix XenApp 6 environment with Citrix Access Gateway for remote working
- Dual-site redundant Exchange 2010 infrastructure with BlackBerry Enterprise Server
- Active Directory domain (running on Windows Server 2008 R2/2012 R2)
- Palo-Alto firewall implementation and security policy design
- PRTG Network monitoring software

The upgrade was phased over a year and my other duties included:

- Support the existing infrastructure under my own intuition
- Support and maintain the existing Citrix XenApp (Presentation Server 4.5) network
- Support the existing Exchange 2003/2007 mixed infrastructure
- Provide support to the end-users and manage the infrastructure of the LOB application Open-I
- Manage the transition from Microsoft Office 2003 to 2010

Experience

Senior Field Engineer

OGL Computer Services Group Limited

Jan 2008 - Feb 2009 1 Years 2 Months

OGL provide IT services to SME and large companies nationwide, they also house a software division which has also enjoyed success providing stock management and process improvement to a variety of industries. As a senior engineer I provided the last line of support for critical equipment on a daily basis and also support end-user's during quieter periods.

- Maintenance and support of HP Proliant & Dell Poweredge
- Working with Server 2003 & 2008 (All versions inc. SBS)
- Advanced Exchange 2003 & 2007
- Finjan, ISA and other proxy solutions
- Close contact with ISP's to resolve WAN and Internet issues
- Support of Watchguard, Cisco and other proprietary VPN solutions
- Often supported 3rd party LOB software or instrumental in incident resolution
- Both local and hosted, email and internet security solutions
- · Citrix and VMWare administration

Field Installation / 2nd Line

Integratech

Sep 2007 - Jan 2008 5 Months

A short-term contract at a medium sized company providing IT services to companies in the SME marketplace in the Midlands and surrounding areas.

- Medium sized IT consultancy company
- Proposed, designed and installed several SME networks
- Working with Windows Server 2003
- Remote support of installations
- Active Directory & Exchange setup
- · Site visits for assessment
- Consultation
- Support and installation of UPS's, Switch & Routers and Servers

2nd Line Support Analyst

Jan 2005 - Jan 2008 3 Years 1 Month

Robert Half International

Robert Half International (RHI) is an international organisation specialising in financial recruitment.

- International Bluechip Company with multiple domains
- Supporting 500+ users in the UK and an additional 1000 in EMEA regions.
- Support of a Server 2003 Active Directory and Terminal Server infrastructure.
- Remote assistance of users, managing user access using AD
- Exchange administration including public folders and mailbox management.
- Support of network printers and central printer servers.
- Process driven, SOX-compliant environment.
- General reactive and proactive server maintenance.
- Software builds of international laptops and desktops
- Site visits in UK and Europe
- Remediation of existing solutions
- Installation of new rack mounted servers, APC UPS's and Cisco switches and routers.
- Support of Avaya PABX and Shoretel VOIP solutions
- Support 100+ users with Blackberry Enterprise Server